Dmitry Markovnikov Minsk, Belarus (relocation is preferable)

E-mail: markovnikovd@gmail.com

Skype: dmitry.markovnikov Cel: +375 (29) 119-19-66

Position

Test QA engineer

Summary

A skilled quality assurance specialist with more than 5 years of experience in testing both web and mobile applications. Extensive experience in testing processes like preparation of test scenarios, defect reporting, test case preparation, test input preparation. Broad knowledge of software and bug life cycle. Knowledge in programming in Python. Advanced English level.

Experience

November 2015 – Present

Test Automation Engineer

Wargaming.net (Minsk, Belarus)

Responsibilities:

- Write, launch and maintain test scripts under Linux/MacOS
- Improve and develop test framework based on python, pytest and docker;
- CI configuration and fails clarification;
- Requirements clarification with developers and management;
- Defect submitting and verification;

October 2015 – Present

Test Automation Engineer

QAprosoft (Minsk, Belarus)

Responsibilities:

- Write, launch and maintain UI test scripts;
- Involved in Android app framework development and automation tests implementation using python and appium;
- Improve and develop test framework based on python, pytest, selenium and docker;
- CI configuration and fails clarification;
- Defect submitting and verification;

November 2015 – November 2016

Test Automation Engineer

Lazada.vn (Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam)

Responsibilities:

- Write, launch and maintain test scripts under Linux/MacOS (using self-designed test framework, based on Python, Pytest, Flask and docker);
- Creating test plans, check lists/test-cases for new features;
- Requirements clarification;
- Defect submitting and verification

November 2014 – November 2015

Test Automation Engineer

epam.com (Minsk, Belarus)

Responsibilities:

- Write, launch and maintain test scripts under Linux (using self-designed test framework, based on Robot framework and Python);
- Manual testing of a product;
- Creating test plans, check lists/test-cases for new features;
- Requirements clarification;
- Defect submitting and verification;

August 2013 – November 2014

QA Engineer

cactussoft.biz (Minsk, Belarus)

Responsibilities:

- Testing mobile applications developed for Android and iPhone.
- Dealing with technical documentation, specification of requirements, daily contact with the product owner.
- Compilation of test cases, dealing with test documentation, providing daily reports on their work.

May 2012 – August 2013

QA engineer

twinslash.com (Minsk, Belarus)

Responsibilities:

- Analysis of the documentation (functional requirements);
- Functional testing.
- Entry of error reports to a bug-tracking system.
- Preparation of test documentation (test cases, checklists).
- Communication with the product owner, analysis, specification of functional requirements for applications;
- Analysis of the quality of applications and their components.

Education	
2007-2012	Higher education: Belarusian State University Department of Physics, bachelor.
2012-2013	Belarusian National Technical University Master of Engineering.
Courses	Software testing courses; Test automation courses;
	Python courses: An Introduction to Interactive Programming in Python; Principles of Computing; lintroduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python
Certificates	ISTQB Foundation Level
Skills	 Programming languages and tools: python, pytest, appium, selenium webdriver, docker, docker-compose Software: Git, Gerrit, Gitlab, CI(Jenkins, Teamcity)
	• Database: MySQL, Postgresql;
	 OS: Windows family (98-8.1, also including server editions – installation and administration), Linux, MacOS, iOS, Android. Management tools: Atlassian Jira+Confluence, Testlink, TesRail, Basecamp, Redmine, Rally, Bugzilla;

• Languages: English (advanced), Russian (native)

Available upon request.

References